(
"ai_sub_version": "3.5.2",
"generated_at": "2026-08-22T13:47:50.063293",
"lyrics_prompt_version": 9,
"subtitles_prompt_version": 18,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"any_pending": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": null,
"model_subtitles": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"model_lyrics": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true,
"max_storage_gb": 18.0
),
"search": (
"qps": 0.3,
"max_length": 4096,
"web_search_tool": "langsearch",
"timeout": 60.0,
"retries": 3,
"min_wait_seconds": 1.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 10.0,
"multiplier": 2.0
),
"validation_buffer_ms": 2000,
"verification_gap_seconds": 60,
"gap_verification_retries": 1,
"gap_verification_ignore_start": true,
"gap_verification_ignore_end": true
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": false,
"fps": 1.0,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"threshold_mb": 20,
"duration_tolerance_ms": 100,
"encoder": null
),
"start_offset_min": 0
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"lyrics": 4,
"subtitles": 4
),
"retry": (
"per_run": 5,
"max_runs": 3,
"multiplier": 2.0,
"min_wait_seconds": 30.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 300
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": true,
"scrub": false,
"progress_bars": true,
"progress_bar_width": 80,
"progress_bar_refresh_seconds": 1.0
)
知らぬ存じぬ 快いのかんで
Feigning ignorance with a pleasant bite,
面倒臭さをしつけられてる
I've been disciplined to bear the annoyance.
何から何まで
From start to finish,
獅子お山で 効くを上手にうなづき合ってる
nodding along smoothly to whatever is asked of me.
仲良しこよしで さあ たまりたまえよ
Being buddy-buddy, come on, pile it on and hoard it!
言えないね そんな強い言葉は
I can't say such strong words,
少しだけ静かにしてほしいね
I'd want you to quiet down a bit.
ああ 私たち待望へ
Ah, toward our long-awaited desire...
てくてくてく歩く ややや
Walking step by step, yeah,
果てその日まで ねねね ねこく やややっと
until that very end, hey hey hey...
あなたのまわりも よよよ 妖怪 せせせ 服 あれあれあれ 約束の地まで
All around you too, until the promised land!
さあ 掲げよう ばってん ばってん てくてくてく歩く ややや
Come on, let's hold it high, marching step by step!
今日も期待 そっちのけで 家になるから
Today too, leaving expectations aside, making it my home—
私ひとりでも やってやる
even if I'm all alone, I'll make it work.
聞きますね
You'll listen, right?
すべてすべてすべて任せてそれをさせてよ大事なことなの分かっているでしょ
Leave everything to me, let me do it. You know it's important, right?
白昼中怪異にの会なまんどくさいまま今日もあそぼうすぎたゆくのでしょう
In broad daylight, a strange gathering... remaining troublesome, let's play today too as time passes by.
壁に水を上げましょう
Let's water the walls,
時の中し折れたこと忘れてた
I forgot how time bent and broke us...
さあだだだだ黙れ黙れ黙れ
Now, blah blah blah, shut up, shut up, shut up!
嫌な嫌なそんな強い言葉は
Such hateful, harsh words—
少しだけ静かにしてほしいね
I want you to quiet down just a little bit.
私たち待望へ
Toward our long-awaited future—
今と未来 見たかったはずなのに
Even though I should have wanted to see the present and future...
世界点々転々ぽくやーややー見えるその日までは
Spinning round and round the world until the day it comes into view—
どんどんどんどんえええええこの世のことはりょりょりょ
Boom boom boom, hey hey hey, the ways of this world, ryo-ryo-ryo—
今はぜんぜんぜんぶくさっさっさあなたの方じゃなく形作るわ
Now, rot everything completely, not your side, I'll shape it myself!
さあ世界点々転々ぽくやーややー果てすその日まで
Now, spinning round and round the world until the endless day—
ねねねねこくやーややーあなたの周りもよよよ
Hey hey hey hey, black cat, yay yay yay, around you too, yo yo yo!
逆回転々々ぽくやーややー白黒あれあれあい
Reverse rotation round and round, black and white, well well, love!
今日もみんな来てくれてありがとうございます
Thank you all so much for coming today too!
続けて歌うので盛り上がっていきましょう 声出せ！
Let's keep singing and get hyped! Make some noise!
はい！はい！はい！はい！
Hey! Hey! Hey! Hey!
朽ち果てた心に i need you 朝のアルカロイド
To a decaying heart, I need you, the morning alkaloid.
あだなはネットの晒し首 かき鳴らせ ディストーション
My nickname is net-exposed execution, strum out distortion!
突き焼き刃の侍が乱れ打ち三弾銃
A half-baked samurai's erratic shotgun barrage,
悲劇の歴史で踊ろうか ほら てんてこへんてこまいまい
Shall we dance in the history of tragedy? Come on, frantic and weird, spinning around!
僕の心はエゴロック 斜め45度 ナセンス
My heart is Ego Rock, at a 45-degree angle, nonsense.
ノウハウ砕いてマンネリを 明日に バイバイバイ
Smash the know-how, say bye-bye-bye to routine tomorrow!
媚びへらうその姿 吐き気の空模様
That flattering posture, the sky's appearance of nausea,
シニカルな視線の雨 今日も両目を塞ぐふり
Cynical rain of glances, pretending to cover both eyes again today.
死にたがるな 獅子の雨 今日も両目を塞ぐふり
Don't wish to die, lion's rain, pretending to cover both eyes again today...
もっともっと声出せるでしょ？皆さん行きますよ！
You can raise your voices even more, right? Everyone, let's go!
はい！はい！はい！はい！
Hey! Hey! Hey! Hey!
おちゃらけ頭に i need you ちまたのアルカロイド
To a jokester's head, I need you, the street's alkaloid.
あの子も流行りの インスタントショー 巻き散らしに会いに行き
That girl too, in a trendy instant show, going out to scatter it around.
うだつが上がらぬ侍が 未来断つ哀悼歌
A struggling samurai's future-cutting elegiac song,
無残な歴史で歌おうよ ほら ちゃんちゃらなんちゃらまいまい
Let's sing in a gruesome history, come on, ridiculous, whatever, spinning around!
はっぴーな心で生きようか 真夏並み hot なミュージック
Shall we live with a happy heart? Midsummer-level hot music!
端折って砕いて丸書いて 明日もわはは
Cut corners, smash it, draw a circle, laugh haha tomorrow too!
洒落臭さも癖になる はみ出し者だろ
Even cheeky audacity becomes a habit, we're outcasts, right?
シニカルな視線の雨 今日も両目を塞ぐふり
Cynical rain of glances, pretending to cover both eyes again today.
リリカルな視線の雨 今日も両目を開くふり
Lyrical rain of glances, pretending to open both eyes again today.
透明な感情は染まるだけさ
Transparent emotions are only dyed,
だったら見て見ぬふりにする奴らを押し出せ
So push out those who turn a blind eye!
人生かけても負けそうです 勝ち負け取り憑かれ ナセンス
Even betting my life, I might lose; possessed by winning and losing, nonsense.
1分砕いて常識を 未来に say goodbye
Smash one minute of common sense, say goodbye to the future!
僕の心はエゴロック 斜め45度 ナセンス
My heart is Ego Rock, at a 45-degree angle, nonsense.
ノウハウ砕いてマンネリを 明日に バイバイバイ
Smash the know-how, say bye-bye-bye to routine tomorrow!
媚びへらうその姿 吐き気の空模様
That flattering posture, the sky's appearance of nausea,
シニカルな視線の雨 今日も両目を塞ぐふり
Cynical rain of glances, pretending to cover both eyes again today.
シニカルな視線の雨 今日も両目を塞ぐふり one two three fuck you
Cynical rain of glances, pretending to cover both eyes again today, one two three fuck you!
繁華街 地下場末のバーは
Down in the slums, at a shady underground bar,
ボンクラ酔いどれ自称非凡人
drunken good-for-nothings call themselves extraordinary.
使い捨てしたいクズと
Trash who just want to be thrown away
晒されいヤカラにて大繁盛
and those exposed by them thrive in the night.
混ざり物多めの安価なバーボン
A cheap bourbon mixed with all sorts of things
半端なアンタがよく似合う
suits a half-baked person like you so well.
酔ったら同じことなんてのがお決まりなんだけど
You get drunk and repeat the same old routine, as always, but...
人は孤独を殺すため
People drink alcohol to kill their loneliness,
虚しさを戻すため酒を飲むんだ
to wash away the emptiness inside.
金も時間も肝臓も
Money, time, and even our livers—
まあ何でもやるからさ
well, we'll give up anything for it, so...
二人でいよう？
Shall we be together?
良いとか悪いとか言うそれ以前に
Long before we talk about right or wrong,
俺には一切記憶がねえんだよ
I don't have a single memory left at all.
明日もまた猛弁解
Tomorrow will bring another fierce excuse;
飲んだら明日に響くと言うけど
they say drinking tonight means a hangover tomorrow, but...
飲まなきゃその明日すらもねえんだよ
if I don't drink, there won't even be a tomorrow!
嫌になるぜもう一杯
It's so frustrating, pour me another cup.
DON'T STOP! 構わずにもう一杯
DON'T STOP! Pour me another without a care!
明日の行方も今夜の便も
Where tomorrow goes, and tonight's flight as well—
全部無くして尚大繁盛
lose it all, and still business thrives.
プライドと理性捨てりゃあ
If you throw away your pride and reason,
愛を偽るのは簡単だ
faking love is an easy task.
「しー」人差し指で黙らせて
"Shh," silencing me with an index finger,
以下略 午前2時
yadda yadda, past 2 a.m.—
結局いつものこととヤマオチまいなんだけど
in the end, it's the usual story with a predictable punchline, but...
人は誰しもが偽善者さ
Everyone is a hypocrite at heart;
優しい嘘を餌に狩りをするんだ
they hunt using gentle lies as bait.
血酒 火の酒 苦い酒
Blood wine, fire wine, bitter wine—
ねぇ優しくするからさ
hey, since I'll be so kind to you,
一人は嫌だ
I hate being alone!
愛だの恋だのやんやと騒ぐが
They make a fuss about love and romance,
酔ったら結局誰でもいいんだよ
but when you're drunk, anybody will do in the end!
荒ぶりて暴言タイム
Acting wild in a verbal abuse time,
その「誰でも」すら俺は選ばれず
even among that "anybody," I'm not chosen,
泣くのもダサせえし酒を浴びんだよ
and since crying is pathetic, I drown myself in booze!
嫌になるぜもう一杯
It's so frustrating, pour me another cup.
CAN'T STOP! 興味もなくもう一杯
CAN'T STOP! Pour me another without a single care!
馬鹿と煙が梯子酒
Fools and smoke go bar-hopping up the ladder,
登る様はさながら蜘蛛の糸
climbing up just like a spider's thread.
何処もかしこもクソだらけって
Everywhere you look is full of crap,
オイ一番クソなのはオマエだ馬鹿
hey, the biggest piece of shit here is you, idiot!
良いとか悪いとか言うそれ以前に
Long before we talk about right or wrong,
俺には一切記憶がねえんだよ
I don't have a single memory left at all.
嫌になるぜもう限界
It's so frustrating, I've reached my limit.
飲んでもいないのに難なく生きてる
You're living so easily without even drinking—
アンタの方こそ飲まれてるんだよ
you're the one who's completely consumed by it!
嫌になるぜもう一杯
It's so frustrating, pour me another cup.
WON'T STOP! 死ぬ前にも一杯
WON'T STOP! Pour me one more cup before I die!
はい連続で3曲聴いていただきましたけどいかがでしょうかかっこよかった？
Well, you've heard three songs in a row. How was it? Was it cool?
おお嬉しいかっこよかった！ありがとうございます今日もね見に来てくださってありがとうございます
Oh, I'm so glad! That's cool! Thank you so much for coming to watch today too.
ええツイートねこちらのハッシュタグ高嶺ルイ1周年ライブでねつぶやいてくれると嬉しいです
Um, if you could tweet about it using the hashtag #TakaneLui1stAnniversaryLive, I'd be so happy.
ということで、すっごい緊張しているんだけれども
So, I'm super nervous right now, but...
おや？ちょっと見てくださいよ、このステージ、高嶺ルイの特別仕様にしていただきました！
Oh? Look at this stage, everyone! They made it a special design just for Takane Lui!
いやステンドグラスでめちゃくちゃ綺麗じゃない？
Isn't it super gorgeous with all the stained glass?
もうね、これ見た瞬間に私もうモチベーションアップアップしちゃって、今日のライブ一生懸命頑張ろうって思いました！
The moment I saw this, my motivation went straight up, and I thought, "I'm gonna do my absolute best in today's live!"
みんなもね、楽しんでくれると嬉しいです。
I hope you all have fun too.
今日はねこのライブグロースというサブタイトルがついているんですけれども
Today's live has the subtitle "Growth," and of course...
アイドルとして、そしてアーティストとして成長するのはもちろんなんですが、みんなとね、ルイ友のみんなと一緒に成長していきたいなという思いを込めてこのサブタイトルをつけました！
while growing as an idol and artist, I put this subtitle here with the wish to grow together with all of you, my fellow Luimates!
これからね、コラボパートに入っていきますので、初めてじゃない？ねぇ私たちが自分の枠でねあの
From here on, we're going into the collaboration part, so isn't this a first? You know, us doing...
歌を歌うのは初めてなのでちょっと楽しみにしていただき、
Since this is my first time singing a song, I hope you'll look forward to it,
最後に重大発表もありますので、最後まで楽しんでいってください！
and there'll be a major announcement at the end, so please enjoy it all the way through!
それでは、準備に…Let's go!
Now then, get ready... Let's go!
Haze you.
She's dressed up in diamond dust
A lover of decay
Coated lashes, soul of ashes
What more can I say?
踏みしめた アリの行列なんて
Stepping on a procession of ants,
気づいてない と誰もが思う
everyone thinks you haven't noticed.
傷ついてない と
Thinking you're not hurt,
誰もが思う 痛い痛い…
everyone thinks... It hurts, it hurts...
Loving you, killing you, isn't it thrilling? You've
said enough from those guts you've been spilling through
crying and begging, a lovely sound, I tear at your soul, but ya still stick around.
What I've found is a treasure indeed, a friend who can bend to my every need,
I'll use and abuse you and never feel bad, until suddenly, funnily, you take my hand.
Tangle you tight in the yarns that I've spun, and I'll do it again to get what I want.
Pretend that I'm harmless, I'm actually alarmed this is something charming to anyone... (wow)
I'll give you fire.
心に飼う
Nurtured in my heart,
Hello? Garou garou
唸りかける
howling out.
また意地悪な
Once again, raising
爪を立てて
my wicked claws
かってあげる
to scratch you.
Haze you.
When the curtains finally close and the show's really over
If you glance into my past, it's just nothing new
Lying, conniving, thriving on hate
I'll tell you it was "all for you."
お聞きなさい
Listen closely:
本当の薔薇は 自分のトゲに
true roses never get hurt
傷ついたりしないものよ
by their own thorns.
ya know,
I want you to care that I want you to stay
So I swear I won't blame you if you turn away
At the end of the day, I will smile and give in
To this burning and vile original sin
Cuz hell is the realization your selfish and drawn to the loving, the soft and the helpless
cuz hell is the realization you're selfish and drawn to the loving, the soft and the helpless.
I can see through that facade that you wear, when you're honest and promise you'll fight the despair
And I'll say it again, that I know I'm the worst, so then how can you spend so much love on the person that hurts you
I'll give you fire.
心に飼う
Nurtured in my heart,
Hello? Garou garou
唸りかける
howling out.
また意地悪な
Once again, raising
爪を立てて
my wicked claws
かってあげる
to scratch you.
Raihou yoi no hao to
urezanka tsui bamu karasu kana
Don't be afraid.
ii ko ne mou wo nemuri
It's okay, now go to sleep.
I'll give you fire.
Just keep it to yourself.
Hello, the hungry wolf has come to give you hell
Once again I'll treat you nice, think twice before you fall
And smile while you do. Love, the me that's killing you.
Garou garou garou
Haze you...
That's me, that's killing you.
Garou garou garou
Haze you.
ロメオ
Romeo
初めまして お嬢様
A pleasure to meet you, my lady,
はじめまして お嬢さん
西の国から 愛のために
from western lands for love,
貴女に会いに来ました
I've come to meet you.
急な話ですがどうか驚かないで
It's sudden, I know, but please don't be surprised,
僕のお姫様にね なってください
would you please be my princess?
悩んでるの? お嬢さん
Are you worried, my lady?
浮かからない顔は似合わないよ
That sad face doesn't suit you.
ほらほら耳を貸してよ
There there, lend me your ear.
もしもし宜しければですが俺と一緒に
If it would please you, won't you run away with me
全て捨てて逃げよう東の国へ
and throw everything away to the eastern land?
寂しそうなその赤い唇に
On those lonely, red lips,
優しい魔法をかけるよ
I'll cast a gentle spell.
さあさドレスに着替えて
Come now, change into your dress,
世界一のお姫様 踊りましょうか?
finest princess of the world, shall we dance?
誰もが貴女を欲しがって
You are sought after by one and all,
僕らを夢中にさせちゃって
driving us into a daze,
奪うよ 愛のKiss
and stealing a love's kiss.
瞳閉じてプレゼント
Close your eyes, a present for you—
空に光るあの星を 二人のものに
that star shining in the sky will be ours.
世界が貴女を欲しがって
The world is longing for you,
俺たち本気にさせちゃって
making us completely serious.
その名は ジュリエッタ
Your name is Juliet!
離れないでお嬢さん
Don't leave me, young lady,
俺のそばではありのままの笑顔でいられるはずだ
you're meant to stay smiling by my side.
命に代えても守り抜きみせます さあおいで
I'll protect you at the cost of my life, come now!
今回はさせない 色褪せない景色へ さあおいで 選んで?
This time I won't let you down, to an unfading scenery, come now, choose?
渡したくない 他の誰かには 譲れないのさ 誰にも
I don't want to hand you over to anyone else, I won't surrender you to anyone!
さあさ 裸足で駆け出せ
Come now, run on your bare feet,
世界一のお姫様 夢の世界へ
finest princess of the world, run to a world of dreams!
不安な想いは消し去って
Rid yourself of your unease,
ちょっぴりルール破っちゃって
break the rules a little,
狙うよ 愛のKiss
aiming for a love's kiss!
手を繋いで連れてくよ
I'll take your hand and lead you away,
海に眠る宝石を 二人のものに
the gems asleep beneath the sea will be ours.
世界が貴女を欲しがって
The world is longing for you,
僕らを本気にさせちゃって
making us completely serious.
その名は ジュリエッタ
Your name is Juliet!
貴女のことしか見えなくて
I have eyes for no one but you,
僕らの本気を魅せちゃって
showing you how serious we are.
その名は ジュリエッタ
Your name is Juliet!
あんたにゃ もったいない
You're too good for you,
あたしゃ本当 NICE BODY
I've really got a nice body!
自分で行うくらい タダじゃない!
If I say so myself, it's not free!
あんたにゃ もったいない
You're too good for you,
あたしゃ本当 NICE BODY
I've really got a nice body!
自分で行うくらい タダじゃない! じゃない?
If I say so myself, it's not free, am I?
熱けりゃ 冷ませばいい
If you're hot, you should cool off,
淋しけりゃ EVERY BODY
if you're lonely, everybody!
恋は DYNAMITE
Love is dynamite,
どんなに不景気だって 恋はインフレクション
no matter how bad the recession is, love is inflation.
こんなに優しくされちゃ みだら
It's indecent to be treated this well,
明るい未来に 就職希望だわ
my future is bright, I hope to find a job!
日本の未来は Wow Wow Wow Wow
Japan's future is wow, wow, wow, wow!
世界がうらやむ Yeah Yeah Yeah Yeah
The world envies it, yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah!
恋をしようじゃないか! Wow Wow Wow Wow
Let's fall in love, wow, wow, wow, wow!
Dance! Dancin' all of the night
恋をしようじゃないか！
Shall we fall in love?!
Wow Wow Wow Wow
Dancin' all of the night
なんだか もの足りない
I feel like something's missing,
どこにたって愛してて欲しいわ
wherever I am, I want you to love me.
自分で伝えるの 恥ずかしじゃない！
I can tell you that myself, I'm not embarrassed!
じゃない！
Not at all!
理想の二人だわ
We're the ideal couple,
憧れよ Everybody Very Very Very
everyone wishes they were us, very, very, very!
誰しも気付いてない
Nobody notices,
恋愛って夢の落とし穴 Mystery
that love is the pitfall of a dream, mystery!
恋は Mystery
Love is mystery.
そんなの不自然だって
Saying that's unnatural,
恋のインサイダー
love's insiders say—
それでも上手にされちゃ
but if it's handled well,
幸せ来る日もキャンセル待ちなのか?
is happiness on a waiting list?
あんたの笑顔は
Your smile
Wow Wow Wow Wow
世界がうらやむ
The world envies
Yeah Yeah Yeah Yeah
夢があるんじゃないか！
We have dreams, don't we?!
Wow
Dance! Dancin' all of the night
日本の未来は
Japan's future
世界がうらやむ
The world envies
恋をしようじゃないか！
Shall we fall in love?!
Dancin' all of the night
モーニング娘。も
Even Morning Musume
あんたもあたしも
Even you and me
みんなも社長さんも
Everyone, even the boss
Dance! Dancin' all of the night
ネバマシーン
Never Machine
回る回るよ カザグルマだよ
Spinning, spinning, the pinwheel spins,
赤白 羽根が 踊ってる
red and white feathers are dancing!
早く走って スピード出せば
Run fast, if you pick up speed,
ピンクになって はころぶ
you turn pink and tumble down!
七転び八起き
Fall seven times, get up eight!
希望がふいに 絶望
Hope suddenly turns to despair,
そこから そこから
from there, from there,
這い上がって 見せろよ
show them you can crawl back up!
まわるまわるよ 人生なんて
Spinning, spinning, life is like
ジェットコースター みたいさ
a roller coaster!
形勢不利も 次のカーブで
Even if you're at a disadvantage, in the next curve
見事に どんぴん返し
you'll pull off a magnificent reversal!
七転び八起き
Fall seven times, get up eight!
最後がどうやら 肝心
In the end, calmness is the key,
冷静 沈着 トップの器
having the poise of a top leader.
回り道でも たどり着ければいいじゃない
Even if you take a detour, as long as you arrive, it's fine!
最後の最後に 笑えば
If you can laugh at the very end,
明日のことよりも 今日が大事
today is more important than tomorrow.
バカなふり ばっかりしてるヤツが
The guy who always plays the fool
いいヤツだったり するんだ
might actually be a great guy!
七回目 転んだら One more time!
If you fall for the seventh time, one more time!
次がチャンスだよ！
Your next chance is here!
僕らは生きているよね
We're alive, aren't we?
じっくり執着をするけど
Obsessing over things in detail, but...
うずくまる気持ちよりの
Rather than crouching in despair,
女神目の前通るの掴め直感目
Catch the goddess passing right before your eyes!
七転び八起き
Fall down seven times, stand up eight.
最後どうやら肝心
The ending is what matters most.
満足？家出君に軍配
Satisfied? Victory goes to you!
回り道でもたどり着ければいいじゃない
Even the long way around is fine if you reach your goal!
最後の最後に笑えば
If you can laugh at the very end,
明日のことよりも今が大事
The present matters more than tomorrow.
ジョークばっかり言ってるアイツが信用できたりするんだ
Sometimes you can even trust the guy who's always joking around.
八回目起き上がれ One more time! 今がチャンスだよ！
Get up on the eighth time! One more time! Now's your chance!
回り道でもたどり着ければいいじゃない
Even the long way around is fine if you reach your goal!
最後の最後に笑えば
If you can laugh at the very end,
明日のことよりも今が大事
The present matters more than tomorrow.
バカなふりばっかりしてるヤツが信用できたりするんだ
Sometimes you can even trust the guy acting like a fool.
七回目転んだら One more time! 次がチャンスだよ！
Fall down seven times, one more time! Next is your chance!
Life is full of ups and downs
君が何かを言いかけて
As you started to say something,
電車が過ぎる高架線
A train passes over the elevated tracks.
動く唇読んできたけど
I tried reading your moving lips, but...
君が何かを言いかけて
You started saying something
電車が過ぎる高架線
As the train passed by the overhead line
動く唇読んできたけど
I tried reading your moving lips, but
YesかNoか?
Was it yes or no?
河川敷の野球場で球を打った金属音
The metallic sound of a ball being hit
黙り込んだ僕らの所へ飛んでくればいい
It would be nice if it flew over
一歩目を踏み出してみなきゃ何もし始まらないよ
If you don't take the first step forward
頭の中で答えを出すな
Don't try to find the answer inside your head
恋をするのはいけないことか?
Is falling in love something wrong?
僕らの両手に飛び込めよ
Jump right into both of my hands
若過ぎる それだけで大人に邪魔をさせない
Just because you're too young won't let adults get in the way
恋をするのはいけないことか?
Is falling in love something wrong?
君の気持ちはわかってる
I already understand how you feel
感情を隠したら
If you hide your emotions
制服を着たマネキンだ
You're just a mannequin wearing a uniform
冬型の気圧配置に
In the winter pressure pattern
心が冷え込みそうだよ
My heart feels like it's freezing over
自販機の缶コーヒー 君の手にあげる
A canned coffee from the vending machine
卒業を待ってみたところで何も変わらないだろう
Even if you wait for graduation, nothing's going to change, is it?
今しかできないチョイスもあるさ
There are choices you can only make right now
どんな自分を守っているのか?
What kind of self are you protecting?
純情の壁壊したんだ
Break down the wall of pure emotion
汚れなきものなんて大人が求める幻想
Things that are completely stainless are just illusions sought by adults
どんな自分を守っているのか?
What kind of self are you protecting?
僕は本気で好きなんだ
I'm seriously in love
その意志はどこにある?
Where does that willpower lie?
制服を着たマネキンよ
You mannequin wearing a uniform
できないんじゃない
It's not that you can't do it
やってないだけさ
It's just that you haven't tried yet
未来の扉そこに在るのに
Even though the door to the future is right there
僕は何度も誘う
I'll invite you over and over again
生まれ変わるのは君だ
The one who will be reborn is you
僕にまかせろ
Leave it to me
恋をするのはいけないことか?
Is falling in love something wrong?
僕らの両手に飛び込めよ
Jump right into both of my hands
若過ぎる それだけで大人に邪魔をさせない
Just because you're too young won't let adults get in the way
恋をするのはいけないことか?
Is falling in love something wrong?
君の気持ちはわかってる
I already understand how you feel
感情を隠したら
If you hide your emotions
制服を着たマネキンだ
You're just a mannequin wearing a uniform
交差点の途中で不安になる
Becoming uncertain in the middle of an intersection
あの信号いつまで青い色なんだろう?
Just how long will that signal stay blue?
ふいに点滅し始め急かすのかな
I wonder if it will suddenly start flashing and rushing us
いつの間にか少し早歩きになっていた
At some point they started walking a little faster
自分の意志関係ないように
As if their own will didn’t matter
誰彼も皆一斉に走り出す
Anyone and everyone started running at once
何に追われ焦るのかと笑う
I laugh wondering what’s driving their haste
客観的に見てる私が嫌いだ
I hate myself for looking so objectively
決心のきっかけは理屈ではなくて
The cause for a decision isn’t reasoning
いつだってこの胸の衝動から始まる
It always starts from an impulse of this chest
流されてしまうこと抵抗しながら
While resisting being washed away
生きるとは選択肢たった一つを選ぶこと
To live is to choose just one of the options
横断歩道渡っていつも思う
Whenever I pass the crosswalk, I always think
こんな風に心に信号があれば良い
If only the heart had signals like these
進みなさいそれから止まりなさい
Continue and then stop
それがルールならば悩まずに行けるけれど
But if those are the rules, then I can continue untroubled
誰かの指示待ち続けたくない
I don’t want to keep waiting for someone’s orders
走りたいときに自分で踏み出せる
Stepping forward whenever I want to run
強い意志を持った人でいたい
I want to be someone who holds a strong will
もう一人の明日の私を探そう
Let’s find tomorrow’s other me
交差点の途中で不安になる
Becoming uncertain in the middle of an intersection
あの信号いつまで青い色なんだろう?
Just how long will that signal stay blue?
ふいに点滅し始め急かすのかな
I wonder if it will suddenly start flashing and rushing us
ふいに点滅し始め
Suddenly it starts flashing,
急かすのかな
urging me on?
いつの間にか 少し 早歩きになってた
Before I knew it, I was walking a bit faster.
自分の意思 関係ないように
As if it has nothing to do with my own will,
誰も彼もみんな 一斉に走り出す
everyone, one and all, starts running at once.
何に追われ焦るのか?と笑う
Laughing, "What are we rushing and chasing after?"
客観的に見てる私が嫌いだ
I hate myself for looking at it so objectively.
決心のきっかけは 理屈ではなくて
The trigger for resolution isn't about logic,
いつだってこの胸の衝動から始まる
it always starts from the impulse in my chest.
流されてしまうこと 抵抗しながら
While resisting being carried away,
生きるとは選択肢 たった一つを選ぶこと
living means choosing just one option.
横断歩道 渡って いつも思う
Crossing the crosswalk, I always think,
こんな風に 心に 信号があればいい
"If only there was a traffic light in my heart like this."
進みなさい それから 止まりなさい
"Proceed, and then stop."
それがルールならば 悩まずに行けるけれど…
If that were the rule, I could go without worrying...
誰かの指示 待ち続けたくない
I don't want to keep waiting for someone else's instructions.
走りたい時に 自分で踏み出せる
When I want to run, I want to take a step forward myself.
強い意思を持った人でいたい
I want to be someone with a strong will.
もう一人の明日の私を探そう
Let's search for another me of tomorrow.
決心のきっかけは 時間切れじゃなくて
The trigger for resolution isn't running out of time,
考えたその上で未来を信じること
but believing in the future after thinking it through.
後悔はしたくない 思ったそのまま
I don't want to have any regrets, just as I thought.
正解はわからない たった一度の人生だ
We don't know the right answer, it's a once-in-a-lifetime life.
ほら 人ごみの誰かが走り出す
Look, someone in the crowd starts running,
釣られたみたいにみんなが走り出す
everyone starts running as if dragged along.
自分のこと 自分で決められず
Unable to decide things for myself,
背中を押すもの 欲しいんだ
I want something to push my back.
きっかけ
The trigger.
決心のきっかけは 理屈ではなくて
The trigger for resolution isn't about logic,
いつだってこの胸の衝動から始まる
it always starts from the impulse in my chest.
流されてしまうこと 抵抗しながら
While resisting being carried away,
生きるとは選択肢 たった一つを選ぶこと
living means choosing just one option.
決心は自分から 思ったそのまま…
Resolution starts from myself, just as I thought...
生きよう
Let's live.
はい、ということで、きっかけを聴いていただきましたー！
Yes, so you've listened to "Kikkake"!
きっかけの途中に、なんと憧れのホロライブのアイドル衣装をいただくことができ、着させていただきました！
In the middle of "Kikkake," I was given the dream Hololive idol outfit and got to wear it!
どう、似合う？似合う？可愛い？
How is it, does it suit me? Does it look good? Cute?
色々ね、あの、こうした方がいいんじゃないか、ああしたほうがいいんじゃないかってちょっと、相談をさせていただき
Various people gave me advice on whether I should do this or that...
こういったね、私に似合う衣裳をいただくことができました！
and I was able to get an outfit that suits me so well!
これもね、みんなのおかげです。ありがとうございます。
This is all thanks to everyone, too. Thank you so much!
そしてね、えー、はっ、なんか緊張しちゃってるまだ、ふふっ
And um... ah, I'm still feeling so nervous, haha.
えー、コラボパート歌って、歌わせていただいたんですが、みんなといかがでしたか？
Um, I got to sing in the collaboration part, how was it for everyone?
お、めちゃよかったかな？
Oh, was it really good?
実は、まあ、たくさんね喋りたいんだけど、ちょっとね尺の方がもうそろそろやばいということで、完結にお話をすると
Actually, well, I want to talk a lot more, but my time is running out soon, so to wrap it up...
あのね、先ほどのきっかけと、なんか制服のマネキンっていうのが私の大好きな乃木坂46さんの曲なんですよ。
Um, the trigger from earlier and "Seifuku no Mannequin" are songs by my favorite, Nogizaka46.
で、作曲者さんが私1回ね、ラジオとかでもお話ししたことがあるんだけど、杉山勝彦さんという私の憧れのね作曲者さんが、あの作った曲でして、私がすごく大好きな2曲だったので今回歌わせていただきました。
And the composer—I've talked about this once on the radio too—is Katsuhiko Sugiyama-san, a composer I admire so much. He wrote those songs, and they are two of my absolute favorites, so I got to sing them this time.
そして、次の曲が最後になるんですけども、実はその最後の曲、えー、今回、えー初披露となるオリジナル曲になります。そして、その曲が、実は杉山勝彦さんに書き下ろしていただきました。
And the next song will be the last one, but actually, that last song will be an original song being performed for the very first time today. And that song was actually written for me by Katsuhiko Sugiyama-san!
そしてですね、まあ、そしてそしてってめちゃくちゃ多いんだけど、えー、歌詞をですね、私が杉山さんと一緒に作らせていただきました！作詞させていただきました！
And, well, I keep saying "and, and," there's so many, um, I actually got to write the lyrics together with Sugiyama-san! I got to write the lyrics!
この曲はね、あのルイトモさん、いつも応援してくださってるルイトモさんに贈るプレゼントになっていますので、ちょっと、まあ、まあ、とりあえず聞いてくれよ。聞いてくれたら、あ、こういう気持ちで書いたのかなっていうのがすごく、なんだろう、ストレートに伝わってくる曲に仕上がったと思うので、ぜひ、ちょっと聞いていただけたら嬉しいです。それでは、聞いてください。
This song is a present for all the Ruitomos who always support me, so... well, just listen to it for now. Once you listen, I think the feelings I put into it will come across really straight and clear, so I'd be very happy if you'd listen to it. Now then, please listen.
大丈夫？泣かないで
"Are you okay? Don't cry,"
私がいつもついてるよ
I'm always by your side.
辛いのを隠しがちな君
You tend to hide when you're hurting.
放って おけないよ
I can't just leave you alone.
大丈夫 泣かないで
It's okay, don't cry,
でも無理に笑わないで
but don't force yourself to smile.
ゆっくり空見上げてよう
Let's slowly look up at the sky together,
似た者同士で
as kindred spirits.
翼を傷めた君 今度は私が支えるから
The next time your wings are hurt, I will support you.
消えかけた夢に涙した日もあったけれど
There were days I wept over a fading dream,
君の言う“大丈夫”で諦めずに来れた
but your "it's okay" kept me from giving up.
まだ遅くないよ ここから始まるストーリー
It's not too late; the story starts right here.
さあ少し休んで 涙を拭いて歩き出そう
Now rest a little, wipe your tears, and start walking.
覚えている？私もある程度折れかけた翼抱いて
Remember? I too held my broken wings,
励ます君に甘えてた ほらあの日のこと
and relied on you to cheer me up—just like that day.
雨上がりの刹那に私たちは強く生まれ変わる
In the fleeting moment after the rain, we are reborn stronger.
心無い声に耳をふさぐ日もあるけど
Though there are days we plug our ears to cruel voices,
味方がここにいる
our allies are right here.
手当は任せてよ
Leave the healing to me!
また増えてゆくよ これから叶えるストーリー
The story we'll fulfill keeps growing from here.
さあ手を取り合って 遥か彼方を見つめよう
Now let's hold hands and gaze far into the distance.
これから先は傷つけずには進めない
From here on, we can't move forward without getting hurt,
だけど覚えていて 君はもう一人じゃないから胸を張って
but remember, you're not alone anymore, so stand tall with pride.
私たち今も不器用で無邪気な小鳥
We are still clumsy, innocent little birds.
譲れない夢抱いて 翼はためかせよう大空へ
Embracing our unwavering dreams, let's flap our wings toward the open sky!
向かい風受けて 高く高く飛び立とう
Facing the headwind, let's fly high, high into the sky!
Facing the headwinds, let's fly high into the sky.
また雨が降り出してても
Even if the rain starts falling once again,
私が守るから
I will protect you.
この先にどんな未来が待ってるか分からない
I don't know what kind of future awaits us ahead,
だけど信じている
but I believe in it.
君とならどこまでもいける
With you, I can go anywhere.
一緒にみる夢のストーリー
The story of the dream we see together.
この後24時から先ほど披露いたしました鷹嶺ルイ2つ目のオリジナル曲「ツバサ」が各種音楽サイトよりリリースされます。
Starting at midnight tonight, my second original song "TSUBASA," which I just performed, will be released on various music sites.
私が憧れておりました数々の乃木坂46名楽曲を作成した杉山勝彦さんに作っていただきました。
It was created by Katsuhiko Sugiyama, whom I've long admired and who has composed many famous Nogizaka46 songs.
作詞には今回私も参加させていただいております。
I also participated in writing the lyrics this time.
みんな悩みや葛藤はあるけれども一緒に手を取って進んでいこうねという前向きな歌詞になっております。
The lyrics are positive, saying that even though everyone has worries and struggles, let's hold hands and move forward together.
私からルイ友さんへの日頃の感謝を込めて作詞をしたのでぜひぜひたくさん聴いてくれると嬉しいです。
I wrote these lyrics with daily gratitude to my Ruitomo, so I'd be so happy if you listen to it a lot.
ミュージックビデオは現在鋭意制作中です。
The music video is currently in production.
こだわって制作しているので少しお時間はいただきますが楽しみにしていてください。
It takes time because we're being very particular about it, but please look forward to it.
そしてそしてこの後私のチャンネルでライブでも歌いました「エゴロック」を公開いたします。
And also, starting right after this, I'll release "Ego Rock," which I sang during the live on my channel.
歌動画を1年間毎月かかさず上げられたのはみんなのおかげです。本当にありがとう。
Being able to upload singing videos every single month for a whole year is thanks to all of you. Thank you so much.
これからも歌も頑張るので楽しみにしていてくださいね。
I'll keep working hard on my singing, so please look forward to it!
鷹嶺ルイ一周年おめでとう！
Happy 1st anniversary, Takane Lui!
おめでとう！ありがとうございます来てくれて
Congratulations! Thank you for coming.
やる気満々ね、歌いてよかった二人ね。
You're so motivated! You two were great singing together.
すいちゃんだったの？
Was it Suichan?
じゃあじゃあ私がかこちゃんかこちゃんで
Then I'll be Kako-chan, Kako-chan!
デカブニでかぶにマイクがちっちゃくなってからね、出直してきてください。
Once your microphones get tiny, come back and try again!
じゃあさようなら、まりんもでかぶに。
Well then, goodbye. Marine is also big!
おめでとう！
Congratulations!
鷹嶺ルイ。おめでとう。
Takane Lui. Congratulations.
え？ありがとうございます。なんか、どうしたんですかそんな格好をつけて。
Eh? Thank you. Why are you posing like that?
鷹嶺ルイ。はい。結婚しよう。
Takane Lui. Yes? Let's get married.
いや、結婚はしないけど、なんかありがとう。みんなちょっと大変だったよね、これね。
No, we're not getting married, but thanks. Everyone had a really tough time with this, didn't they?
いや本当に大変だったね。この同期でできてよかった、同期3人でね。
Yeah, it really was. I'm so glad we could do this as the three gen-mates.
おめでとう！おめでとう！
Congratulations! Congratulations!
よいしょ、4期生や！いつもね、ありがとうございました。
Yoisho, 4th Gen! Thank you as always.
いやでも本当にこの3人でね、なんか6人のフォーメーションダンスできてめちゃくちゃ嬉しかったです。ありがとうございます。
But truly, being able to do a 6-member formation dance with these three made me so happy. Thank you so much.
すごい大変だった。すごい楽しんでいただけたのではないでしょうか
It was so tough. I hope you all enjoyed it immensely!
ということで、明後日はね、クロエ。はい。頑張りよー！
So, the day after tomorrow is Chloe. Yes, do your best!
おめでとう！それなりに頑張ります！
Congratulations! I'll do my best in my own way!
ルイルイ一周年おめでとう！
Happy 1st anniversary, Lui-lui!
ありがとうございます来てくれて嬉しい！嬉し、嬉しい！
Thank you so much for coming, I'm so happy! So, so happy!
いやカッコよくね、歌えましたね、わたたちの。
Man, we sang so coolly, didn't we, Wata-tachi.
なんで？
Why?
なんでこの3人でさ…
Why these three...
なんとなくこの3人がいいかなぁって、なんとなくね。
Just somehow thought these three would be good, you know.
なんとなくなんです。
Just somehow.
なんとなくです、なんとなくです。
Just somehow, just somehow.
ここで出会うと思ってたよね
I thought we'd meet here.
ちょっとね、期待してきちゃったの
I kind of came with expectations.
じゃあ来年、なんとなくまた呼んでもらえたら…
Well then, maybe next year, if you could invite me again...
来てくれるんですか？なんとなく。
Will you come? Somehow.
なんとなく来る。なんとなくOKしてくれる。
Somehow come. Somehow say OK.
なんとなく来ます。
Somehow I'll come.
…and You!
...and You!
じゃあなんとなくマネキンのポーズして終わりにしよう。
Well then, let's end with a mannequin pose somehow.
せーの、たすっ
Ready, go!
はい、ここでも1周年記念のオリジナルグッズの紹介をさせていただきます。
Now, I'd like to introduce the original goods for my 1st anniversary right here.
きゅるどーん！
Kyuru-doon!
はい、ということで今回はですね、おうちデートをテーマにですね、作らせていただきました。
Yes, so this time, we made this with the theme of an "at-home date."
もうすでに可愛いこの画像だけでね(笑)
Just this cute image alone is already adorable.
ということで1つずつ紹介していきましょう。
So let's introduce them one by one.
まずは、こちら！
First, this one!
マイロ先生描き下ろしの2層アクリルパネルになっております。私のね、大好きなマイロ先生に描いていただきました。
It's a two-layer acrylic panel newly drawn by Mayro-sensei. My beloved Mayro-sensei drew it for me.
こちらを飾ってね、ちょっとルイと一緒に過ごしてるみたいな、妄想していただけたらなと思うんですけれども…
If you display this and daydream as if you're spending time together with Lui...
まあ、そういう妄想にはね、温かい飲み物が必須ということで、続いてはこちら！
Well, for such daydreams, a warm drink is essential, so next is this!
トウミ先生描き下ろしのルイとおそろタンブラーもね、今回発売させていただきます。
An "Lui & matching" tumbler newly drawn by Toumi-sensei is also on sale this time.
いやめちゃくちゃ可愛い！ここにおね、温かいお茶を入れて、ちょっと先ほどね、アクリルパネルを見ながら、ちょっとしっぽりとね、うん、妄想していただければなと思うんですけれども…
It's so cute! Put some warm tea in here, and while looking at the acrylic panel from earlier, relax and daydream...
続いて、お目玉商品、こちら！
Next, the centerpiece product, this!
ふわもちつみれ＆つくねクッションということで、肌触りにもすごくこだわったクッションになっていまして、ふわふわ、もちもちってするのでね、ぜひ抱きしめてもちもちと過ごしてください。
The "Fuwamochi Tsukune & Tsukune Cushion"! We were very particular about the texture, so it's fluffy and chewy, please hug it and spend a cozy time.
いやこういうねクッションは何個あってもいいですからね。
You can never have too many cushions like this.
はい！で、今回もルイ描き下ろしシナリオのボイスも販売しております。全部すべて買っていただきますと、特別に、えー、ポストカードがついてまいります。
Yes! And this time as well, voice tracks with scenarios newly written by Lui are on sale. If you buy everything, specially, um, a postcard will be included.
前回ねお誕生日のときには直筆サインだったんですけれども、今回は箔押しサインで、直筆サインメッセージをつけまして、お届けさせていただきます。
Last time for my birthday it was handwritten signatures, but this time with hot-stamped foil signatures and handwritten message, we will deliver it to you.
今回も無制限なので、ゆっくりとね、何買おうかなって、まあセットで買わないと、あの、ついてこないんだけど(笑)、ぜひぜひ買って頂けたらなと思います。
This time it's also unlimited, so take your time and think about what to buy—well, it doesn't come unless you buy the set (laughs)—I hope you'll definitely buy it.
そして、この後ね、メンバーシップ限定のライブもありますので、ぜひメンバーシップに入って待機していただけると嬉しいです。メンバーシップライブも頑張るぞー！待っててねー！
And after this, there's a membership-exclusive live stream, so I'd be happy if you joined the membership and waited. I'll do my best for the membership live too! Wait for me!